Kautzar Alibani

Email : <u>kalibani.ka@gmail.com</u> Phone/Whatsapp/Telegram : (+62) 87822946362

Linkedin : https://www.linkedin.com/in/kautzar-alibani-04954613b/

Github : https://github.com/kalibani

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

Hello there, I'm from Indonesia and currently working for an international company based in Dubai. I have 5 years experience as a frontend software engineer. I have a BS degree in Computer Science and also have joined an intensive programming bootcamp for 6 months which gave me a comprehensive view about what I can do as a programmer. My skills include, but are not limited to: React-Redux, React Native, Vue-Vuex, Web 3.0, Node.js and have experience in web & mobile hybrid development. I am a perseverance programmer, love to learn, explore and implement new tech. Also, have good communication between the team and stakeholders.

FUNCTIONAL EXPERTISE

- Javascript / Typescript / Html & Css/Scss
- React / Next js / React Native -Redux
- Vue / Nuxt js Vuex / Pinia
- Web 3 methodologies (Ethers.js, Thirdweb SDK, Solidity)
- Realtime engine socket.io / Firebase

- Node.js & Express
- Git / Github / Bitbucket / Gitlab
- CI/CD Using Gitlab Pipeline and AWS S3
- PWA (Progressive Web App)
- Deployment Google Cloud
 Platform, AWS S3, Heroku, Netlify

RELEVANT PROJECTS

Crowdfunding Platform - Web 3 Smart Contract Implementation
Role : Full Stack Developer - Solo project
Language : React JS, Solidity, Thirdweb, Hardhat

Project Description : Web 3 Smart Contract Implementation on top of ethereum

sepolia test network

Release : <u>Crowdfunding Platform</u>

Repo : Crowdfunding Github Repositories

OpenSea Clone - NFTs marketplace clone application

Role : Solo project

Language : Next js, Web 3.0 Methodologies, thirdweb, Metamask

Project Description : OpenSea clone blockchain Application

Release : https://open-sea-blockchain-kautzar.vercel.app/
https://open-sea-blockchain-kautzar.vercel.app/
https://open-sea-blockchain-kautzar.vercel.app/

Postpay - Shop Now, Pay later

Role : Senior Frontend Engineer **Language** : React Typescript - Vite, GraphQL

Project Description : Pay later platform Release : https://postpay.io/

Krypt - Send Crypto across the world

Role : Solo project

Language : React js, Web 3.0 Methodologies, Solidity, Metamask

Project Description : Decentralized Application for sending Crypto across the world

Release : https://krypt-web3-react.netlify.app/
https://github.com/kalibani/web3.0-App

Atlan Modern Data Workspace

Role : Senior Frontend Engineer

Language : Vue 3, Pinia, Vite

Project Description : Building a home for data teams

Release : https://atlan.com/

PermataNet E-Banking

Role : Lead Frontend Engineer

Language : React-Redux

Project Description : Revamp E-Banking Permata Bank **Release** : https://www.permatanet.com/pnet/

Brick Website

Role : Freelance/Part time Senior Frontend Engineer

Language : React - Redux

Project Description: Open Payment SASS Application

Release : https://www.onebrick.io/

Mile App Logistics Platform

Role : Freelance/Part time Senior Frontend Engineer

Language : Vue - Vuex

Project Description : Logistics Software Platform

Release : https://mile.app/

LMS Kemenhan Web App

Role : Freelance/Part time Frontend Engineer

Language : Nuxt js - Vuex **Project Description** : E-Learning Web App

OTU Chat - (Deactivated)

Role : Freelance/Part time Senior Frontend Engineer

Language : React Native

Project description: Messenger and Payment App

Frameworks and Libraries : React Native

Release :

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.eklanku.otuChat&hl=in

Modal Rakyat P2P Platform

Role : Software Engineer - Frontend

Language : Node JS (Express) - Javascript (React-Redux)
Project Description : Building and maintaining peer to peer lending web

application using Node js as backend services, Docker as it's

containers and React as a UI javascript library

Release : https://www.modalrakyat.id/

Modal Rakyat Back Office CMS Platform

Role : Frontend Engineer

Language : Node JS (Express) - Javascript (Vue JS)

Project Description : Building admin platform for handling back office process

Release : https://bo.modalrakyat.id

Simple PWA

Role : Frontend Engineer

Language : React js

Project description : Simple Progressive Movie List Web App built in react js

Release : https://whispering-castle-94998.herokuapp.com

FindWork Web-App

Role : Frontend Engineer

Language : PHP (Laravel) - Javascript (Vue JS)

Project Description: Implementing design web-app based on UI/UX designer using

bootstrap and vue is

Release : https://www.findwork.io/

Ecommerce

Role : Solo Project
Language : Javascript

Project description: Develop Simple Ecommerce website,

The server side (REST API) was built with NodeJS, Express and MongoDB. At the front side, I am use VueJs altogether with

Semantic UI

Source-Code : https://github.com/kalibani/ecommerce
Release : http://ecommerce.kautzaralibani.com

To-do Fancy

Role : Solo Project

Project Description : A fancy to-do list application

Language : Javascript

Frameworks and Libraries : NodeJs, ExpressJs, VueJs, MongoDB BootstrapCSS

Source-Code : https://github.com/kalibani/todo-fancy-client &

https://github.com/kalibani/Todo-Fancy-server

Release : http://todofancy.kautzaralibani.com

Kanban Realtime.

Role : Solo project
Language : Javascript

Project description : Kanban is a lean method to manage and improve work

across

human systems.

Frameworks and Libraries : NodeJs, ExpressJs, Firebase, VueJs, BootstrapCSS

Source-Code : https://qithub.com/kalibani/Kanban-Realtime

Release: https://vuejs-firebaseapp.com/#/

(please open in two / more browser to see a real time feature)

Hacktiv-OverFlow

A Mini Version of Stack Overflow Apps

Role : Solo project

Language : Javascript

Project description: Question-Answer Platform App

Frameworks and Libraries : Node Js, Express Js, Vue Js, MongoDB Bootstrap CSS

Source-Code : https://github.com/kalibani/HacktivOverflow

https://github.com/kalibani/HacktivOverFlow-API

Release : http://hacktivoverflow.kautzaralibani.com/

Online House Selling

Role : Solo project
Language : Javascript

Project description : Simple ecommerce platform for online house selling **Frameworks and Libraries** : Node Js, Express Js, Vue Js, MongoDB, Bootstrap CSS

Source-Code :

https://github.com/kalibani/Online-House-Selling-Client/tree/master/client

https://github.com/kalibani/HacktivOverFlow-API

EDUCATION

Bootcamp (Full-Stack Web & Mobile Hybrid Development)

Hacktiv8 (Jakarta,

Indonesia) 2017

BS (Computer Science) Indonesian Computer University, (Bandung, Indonesia) Feb, 2017

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Company : Postpay Technology Limited May 2022 – Present (Dubai - UAE)

Position : Senior Frontend Engineer

Postpay is a pay later platform with a very simple widget to use. As a Senior Frontend Engineer i am responsible to built the feature, manage source code, maintain structure of the app, review and maintaining code

- Built a rich feature app.
- Create a pixel perfect component and UI based on figma design

- GraphQL Integration
- Review and maintain source code.
- communicate and Collaborate with other teams about best practice of software development

Company : Atlan May 2021 – May 2022 (India)

Position : Senior Frontend Engineer

Atlan is an international modern data workspace company with a diverse team and environment. As a Senior Frontend Engineer i am responsible to build the feature, manage source code, maintain structure of the app, review and maintain code.

- Create a pixel perfect component and UI based on figma design.
- Complete ownership of the module & feature.
- Code, test, ship & iterate.
- Review and maintain source code.
- Mentoring intern fellow engineers.
- communicate and Collaborate with other team members to deliver winning products.

Company : Infosys Apr 2019 – May 2021

Position : Lead Frontend Engineer

As a Tech Lead Frontend Engineer i am responsible to manage the team, mentoring the junior, determine stack and tech, review and maintain code.

- Leading and managing a team of frontend engineers to deliver winning products.
- Driving release and sprint planning sessions.
- Get involved in determining stack and tech.
- Design architecture of client side Application.
- Design and implementation of backend services.
- Review and maintain code.
- Collaborate and communicate with other teams and stakeholders about best practice of software development.

Company : Mile App - Part time May 2019 – May 2020

Position : Senior Frontend Engineer

As a Senior Frontend Engineer i am responsible to build the feature, manage source code, make a decision about stack and tech, review and maintaining code

- Design architecture of client side Application.
- Build a feature.
- Review and maintain source code management.
- Lead a team in a weekly sharing session.
- communicate and Collaborate with other teams about best practice of software development.

Company : PT Modal Rakyat Indonesia Apr 2018 – Apr 2019

Position : Frontend Engineer

As a Frontend Engineer, i responsible to deliver design UI and it's functionality

• Writing readable, maintainable and reusable code.

- Implementing design from sketch zeplin to real design using Html/Scss (Slicing)
- Build a feature and it's functionality using React Redux (main p2p web app) & Vue Js Framework (back office cms)
- Collaborate and communicate with other teams about best practices of software developers.

Company : FindWork.io Sep 2017 – Apr 2018

Position : Frontend Engineer

As a Frontend Engineer, i responsible to deliver design UI and it's functionality

- Writing readable, maintainable and reusable code.
- Build a feature and it's functionality using VueJs Framework